# PRAVEEN KUMAR ALUGOJU

**UI Developer** 

Hyderabad India, 500092 +91 8374423442

prven04@gmail.com

## **OBJECTIVE**

UI Developer with 4+ Years of experience and specialization in developing User Interface (UI) web applications using HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap, SASS, JavaScript, Angular2+, React and Next.JS

Extensive experience in create beautiful web applications using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JSON, Bootstrap and Angular, React

Hands on experience in developing user interfaces (providing responsiveness to application) for various resolutions such as Desktop, Mobile, and Tablet.

Working knowledge and thorough exposure on cross browser / cross device compatibility and troubleshooting existing code using Firebug, Chrome and IE developer tools, with emphasis on Responsive Design principles and Interactive Web Design from a simple transition effect to rich media presentations.

work closely with other front-end developers, UX and back-end developers to create working applications that meet Business needs.

Participate in code reviews and ensures that all solutions are aligned to predefined design specifications. Good in software engineering best practices (e.g. code reviews, design documentation)

Estimated time to develop for all approved prototypes and the implementation of those prototypes using JavaScript and CSS as well as showing to project leads and receiving and implementing any changes or implementation updates

Expert Working knowledge on CSS Flexbox and CSS Grid layout models.

Performed complete application life cycle functions from conception to final release to users including Design/Analysis, Implementation, Testing, Deployment and Maintenance.

Experience in using the latest approaches including MVC in the browser, Hands on experience in creating components using Angular 2+

Responsibilities include bug fixing, adding feature requests, enhancements and new development.

Work closely with application testers while testing the usability of the application. Performed multiple assignments under pressure and consistently met deadlines given.

Capable of quickly learning and delivering solutions as an individual and as part of a team.

Worked directly with customers to understand their existing applications and design the site according to their system requirements, and project timelines.

## **SKILLS**

UI Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, SASS, Responsive Web

Design, Prime NG, Angular Material, Angular 6+, React with Redux, Next.js,

Povelopment Tools: Visual Studio Code, Notoned L. Eclipse, Sublime Toyl

**Development Tools:** Visual Studio Code, Notepad++, Eclipse, Sublime Text

Version Control: Git
Testing Frameworks: Jest

Monitoring Tools: Amplitude, Sentry, Track JS, AWS App Sync

### **WORK HISTORY**

UI Developer, Intraedge Technologies, May 2022 to present.

React.js Developer, Byndr Technologies Pvt Ltd, Jan 2021 to Apr 2022

Software Developer, Synerg Technology(INDIA) Pvt Ltd, Jan 2021 to Dec 2021

Formerly worked as Associate Professors in Jayamukhi Institute of technological science

from Aug 2015 to Jan 2021(Non-Technical)

## **EDUCATION**

M.Tech in Computer Science | Jayamukhi Institute of Technological Sciences, JNTU-H, Hyderabad

B.Tech in Computer Science | Sreekavitha Engineering College, JNTU-H, Khammam

Intermediate (10+2) | Ushodaya Junior College, Warangal

SSC | Board of SSC, Zaffargadh

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Snap Finance**

[Duration]: 3 Years+ (Current Project)

[Client]: Snap

[skillset]: Angular 11+, Typescript, JavaScript, React.js, Next.js

# [Responsibilities]

- Developed functionalities using JavaScript, angular 11+ and later with React as well.
- Developed functionalities on various pages to track the events using Amplitude Analytics.
- Implemented Chat boot to communicate with Snap Application using Nice In-Contact Widget.
- Used Track JS, Sentry as the bug tracking system to track and maintain the history of bugs/issues on everyday basis.
- Implemented Split.IO to see the different view by dividing split on specific page.
- Made some performance improvements to user interface by introducing Graph QL.
- Used JEST for running unit test cases.

## **Bench Mark Education University**

[Duration]: 4 Month [Client]: Bench Mark

[skillset]: React.js, Next.js, JavaScript

## [Responsibilities]

- Developed functionalities using Functional Hooks.
- Worked on state specs, props and events to create interactive React JS components.
- Extensively used CSS preprocessor like LESS for re-usable style components.
- Managed state within the ap using Redux and persisted certain parts of the state to device via Redux Persist.
- Used Oops concepts to develop UI Components that could be reused across the web application
- Well aware of deployment process in CI/CD pipelines and monitoring the changes to DEV Environment.
- Experienced in using different JavaScript based packages libraries like Node.js, D3.js for complementary support to the web-based application.

## **PLANCK Finance Project**

[Duration]: 11 Month

[Client]: FOCSFI

[skillset]: Angular 6+, TypeScript, JavaScript

## [Responsibilities]

- Analysing user stories and understanding the legacy application.
- Developed functionalities using Angular8 with prime NG features.
- Used extensively the Git tool for managing the code through VS Code.
- Used Angular Dynamic Reactive Forms concept to implement form setup and complex validations.
- Implemented various functionalities using custom components like v3 advanced table Grid, Typeahead and tree view components. Toggle Button, Multi-Level labels and few other Components for fulfilling project requirements.

PERSONAL INFO DATE OF BIRTH : 03<sup>rd</sup> Aug 1991

NATIONALITY : Indian

**CONTACT NUMBER** : 8374423442

page 3 PraveenKumar Alugoju